alphadictionary.com 2014-04-21

# Privacy Policy - alphaDictionary * Free English Online Dictionary

### Link: alphaDictionary.com Privacy Policy for Kids

## Purpose

Lexiteria, LLC (owner and operator of alphaDictionary.com) understands the power that the Internet holds for changing people's lives, expanding their horizons and enhancing the ease with which they access vital information from around the world. The purpose of our privacy policy is to inform you, as a welcome visitor to alphaDictionary, of the kinds of information we may gather about you when you visit alphaDictionary, how we may use that information, whether we might disclose it to anyone and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information. Our privacy policy and practices are detailed below and we ask you to read them carefully.

## Coverage

Please note that this policy applies to alphaDictionary, Lexiteria and Web sites that carry the alphaDictionary brand or trademark, and not to other companies' or organizations' Web sites to which we link. We have clearly marked alphaDictionary and these branded Web sites with our logo so you know where this policy applies. Linked partners, advertisers and third party Internet sites and services, who may collect data in connection with sweepstakes, promotions, e-commerce, etc., have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of alphaDictionary. We encourage you to read those policies whenever you visit their sites. alphaDictionary has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

## Information About All alphaDictionary Visitors

In general, our service automatically gathers certain usage information like the numbers and frequency of visitors to our Web site and each of its areas or pages, very much like television ratings that tell the networks how many people tune in to a program. We only use such data in the aggregate. We may use this aggregated information to evaluate which products and services are successful and which ones are not, and in order to evaluate which new services we should make available on our Web site. This collective data helps us determine how much our customers use each part or page of the Web site, so we can improve our site to assure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many of you as possible. We also may provide statistical information, never information about you personally, to our partners about how our members, collectively, use alphaDictionary. We do this so our partners too can understand how much people use their sites and our site in order for them to provide you with the best possible Web experience.

## Third Party Relationship

Whenever you provide registration information on co-branded sites, that data may be shared with our media partners. You should make every effort to read these privacy policies, and make an informed decision whether or not to continue based upon these sites' privacy practices and your own discretion.

In addition to finding co-branded sites, you will find direct links on our site to sites offered by third parties. Some of these sites are authorized to use the alphaDictionary brand and/or logo. alphaDictionary carefully evaluates all parties that are authorized to use its brand and/or logo, and believes that all such sites have adopted acceptable privacy policies. Some sites are not authorized to use the alphaDictionary brand or logo and we do not necessarily approve or endorse the privacy policies at these sites. Again, you should read the privacy policies at these sites and make an informed decision whether or not to continue based upon these sites' privacy practices and your own discretion. No third party sites are covered by our Privacy Policy.

alphaDictionary provides certain wholly and totally anonymous statistical information to third parties in aggregate form in order to facilitate the sale of advertising and the sponsorship of services on our site. This information contains no personal information about any visitor to our site; that is, no names, addresses, telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, and the like.

## Registration

You can visit alphaDictionary and use many of our services without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. The vast majority of our services do not require any form of customer registration. However, we do require registration for the use of a few services.

We may specifically ask for information about you when you sign up to use a specific service or when you order a product. We will need certain information—such as name, e-mail address or screen name, billing address, type of computer, credit card number—in order to provide that service or product to you. We may also use that information to let you know of additional products and services about which you might be interested. In addition, it may be shared with third parties who assist alphaDictionary in producing its Web sites or who offer a product or provide a service to our users.

You may choose not to receive such information if you don't want to by letting us know on the registration screen when you sign up for the product or service.

## Disclosure

We do not use or disclose any information about you, your visits to alphaDictionary, or information that you may give us, such as your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number, income, interests, or occupation to any entity outside alphaDictionary. Period. But as we mention above, we may share with our Web site partners aggregated (nonpersonal) statistical information about the use of the alphaDictionary website in general. In short, alphaDictionary will never share any personal information that you provide us during registration with any third parties unless required by law to do so.

During your use of our site and our services, we may collect demographic and profile data about you. We use this data to personalize your experience at our site, showing you content that we think you will be interested in, and displaying the content according to your preferences. We will never share this information with any other entity. Period.

In certain special cases, we may disclose user information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to persons or rights, property or operations or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We may also disclose user information when we believe the law requires it, or in response to any legitimate demand by law enforcement authorities in connection with a criminal investigation.

## Special Attention to Kids

alphaDictionary takes even more care to protect the safety and privacy of young people using our services. We do not any collect information specifically about children and believe that children should get their parents' consent before giving out any personal information. We encourage you to participate in your child's experience in cyberspace.

## Contests

From time to time, we may run contests on our site in which we ask participants for contact information, such as their e-mail addresses. If you participate in contests, your contact information will be used primarily to reach you in connection with the contests. We may also use the collected contact information to send you information about alphaDictionary and our services, as well as offers tailored to your interests by our advertisers and sponsors. You may opt out of receiving such mailings at the time you receive such information. When you register for a service or product at alphaDictionary and later choose to discontinue the service or purchase no more products, we will keep your registration information on file in case you wish to opt back in or purchase another product at a later date. We may send you mailings of special offers even if you have not purchased anything recently or are currently unsubscribed from any of our services. In the event that you wish to remove information about yourself completely from our mailing lists, you may send e-mail directly to alphaDictionary and we will have all your personal information removed from our database.

## Credit Card Processing and Safety

Shopping with alphaDictionary is absolutely safe: you don't have to worry about credit card safety when you are shopping at our site. We guarantee that each purchase you make is protected and safe. If fraudulent charges are ever made, you will not have to pay for them. Your credit card and billing information cannot be read as it travels to our ordering system. To ensure that your information is even more secure, once we receive your credit card information, we do not store it. We currently do not retain any information about your credit card number unless you have chosen automatic renewal for a subscription. In this case, your credit card number is encrypted so that even employees at alphaDictionary can only see the final four digits.

## Order Forms

alphaDictionary uses an order form for customers to purchase products and services or make charitable contributions to one or more non-profit organizations. If you place an order at a store hosted by alphaDictionary or make a contribution, we will collect information from you, including your credit card and contact information. This information will be used by the merchant or non-profit institution to bill the user for products and services or contribution. Contact information from the order form will also be used to ship orders, to contact a user for customer service related issues, and to send the user information about our company and, on occasion, promotional material from some of our partners. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings.

## Your Voluntary Disclosures

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily and publicly disclose personal information on any online service or Web site - for example in our Agora, through e-mail, or similar means, that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Furthermore, while we strive to protect your personal information, alphaDictionary cannot ensure or warrant the security of all information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

## Cookies and How alphaDictionary Uses Them

alphaDictionary uses a web device nicknamed "cookies" that tells us how and when pages in our site are visited, and by how many people. alphaDictionary cookies do not collect personally identifiable information and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personally identifiable information to tell us who you are or even what your screen name or e-mail address is.

A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We use cookies to help us provide customizable services, such as memorizing your user name and password, so that you don't have to type it in each time you visit. We might also store your zip code in a cookie to enable us to show you local information each time you visit our site. Cookies also make Web surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you are on our Web site. alphaDictionary uses cookies to ensure that you do not see the same advertisements too often (once per visit), but they also may collect information about you when you view or click an advertisement at our site.

Our site uses cookies to speed navigation, keep track of items, and provide you with custom tailored content. We also use cookies to remember information you gave us so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the site. By showing us how and when shoppers use the site, cookies also help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the site are based on data such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.

Cookies are never used to gather financial, personal, political or other information about you. You can choose whether to accept the cookies that we or other third parties send to you by changing the settings of your browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies, or to allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept these cookies, your experience at our site or other sites may be diminished and some features may not work as intended.

## Use of IP Addresses

An IP address is a set of numbers that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you log in to your Internet service provider or through your company's local area network (LAN) or wide area network (WAN). Web servers, the big computers that provide Web pages for viewing, automatically identify your computer by the IP address assigned to it during your session.

alphaDictionary may collect IP addresses for purposes of system administration, to report aggregate user information to our advertisers, and to audit the use of our Web site. We do not link a user's IP address to anything personally identifiable to that user, which means that your session will be logged, but you remain anonymous to us. However, we can and will use IP addresses to identify users of our Web site when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our site's terms of use or terms of service, the laws of the land, or to protect our service, site, or other users.

## Security

alphaDictionary operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection. alphaDictionary has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. All sensitive credit information supplied by users is transmitted via Secured Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted in alphaDictionary 's databases as stated above.

Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us. For example, we impose strict rules on alphaDictionary employees who have access either to the databases that store user information or to the servers that host our services.

## Contacting Us

Lexiteria, LLC  
2459 Smoketown Road  
Lewisburg, PA 17837  
USA  

alphaDictionary reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without notice. All changes will be posted to this page
